Mss.Rec.157 Mss.Rec.157
American Philosophical Society
Thompson-Salish language recordings
1990-1992
Mss.Rec.157
American Philosophical Society
45.0 Tape(s)
Linguistic field recordings of Nlaka'pamuctsin, also known as the Thompson, Ntlakyapamuk, or Nlaka'pamux language. Primary consists of grammatical and lexical elicitations sessions. Also includes various brief narratives about wood gathering, picking berries, hunting, fishing, digging for roots, basket making, food preparation, and childhood memories. Recorded by Paul Kroeber in Lower Nicola and Merritt, British Columbia, from October 1990 to March 1992 with consultants Mabel Joe and Kathy York.
45 sound cassettes (39 hr., 57 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Joe, Mabel
Kroeber, Paul D.
York, Kathy
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Paul D. Kroeber in 1992 (Acc. 1992-652r). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Arrangement note
Original tapes numbered TH-K 9 to TH-K 53 by collector.
Related Archival Materials
Extensive field notes from these recordings, prior recording sessions, and related linguistic fieldwork are available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Berries--Harvesting; Fishing; Fuelwood gatherers; Hunting; Ntlakyapamuk Indians; Ntlakyapamuk Indians--Food; Ntlakyapamuk Indians--Social life and customs; Ntlakyapamuk language; Ntlakyapamuk language--Grammar; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-15; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:27; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Lower Nicola (B.C.); Ntlakyapamuk language--Grammar
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-15; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:51; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-16; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:27; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-16; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:27; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-17; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:08; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-17; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:12; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-17; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:58; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-17; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:47; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-18; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:16; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
    Scope and Contents note
    Partially corrected line hum from 12:25 to 15:28. Portions of the speech in this section are minimally audible.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-18; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:21; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
    Merritt (B.C.); Ntlakyapamuk language--Grammar
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-18; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:08; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-18; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:46; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-19; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:25; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-20; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:10; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-19; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:10; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-19; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:10; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-19; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:08; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1990-10-19; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:33; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-03-11; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:12; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation and lexical data, 1991-03-11; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:12; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
    Includes brief discussion at 27:00 of an earlier group of Ntlakyapamuk Indians who died out.
    Merritt (B.C.); Ntlakyapamuk Indians--History; Ntlakyapamuk language--Grammar
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-03-11; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:33; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-03-12; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:13; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-03-12; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:13; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-03-12; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:53; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-03-13; 14-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:13; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
    Uncorrected hum from 22:58 to 25:31.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-03-13; 14-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:14; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-03-14; 15-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:15; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-03-14; 15-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:16; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-03-15; 16-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:14; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-03-15; 16-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:16; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-05-30; 17-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:02; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
    1:04 of pure line noise was removed at :21 mark. The deleted section is represented by a three-second silent gap.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-05-30; 17-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:02; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-05-31; 18-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-05-31; 18-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-05-31; 19-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:09; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-05-31; 19-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:43; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-01; 20-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:19; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
    Merritt (B.C.); Ntlakyapamuk Indians; Ntlakyapamuk language--Grammar
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-01; 20-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:19; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-06-01; 21-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:17; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-06-02; 22-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:05; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-06-02; 22-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:50; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-03; 23-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:17; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-03; 23-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:17; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-03; 24-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:50; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-04; 24-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:11; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-06-04; 25-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:17; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-06-05; 25-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:17; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-06-05; 26-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:49; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-06-05; 26-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:03; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-06-10; 27-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-06-15; 27-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-11; 28-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:19; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-11; 28-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:00; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-12; 29-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-12; 29-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:04; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-14; 30-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:17; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-14; 30-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:23; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Three Ntlakyapamuk narratives followed by translations, 1991-06-14; 30-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:42; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
    Three short narratives given in Ntlakyapamuk through 6:11, followed by free translations into English.
    Berries--Harvesting; Fishing; Hunting; Lower Nicola (B.C.); Ntlakyapamuk Indians--Food
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-15; 31-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-16; 31-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:17; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-16; 32-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-16; 32-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Narrative on the speaker's childhood memories of elders and the eating and preparation of food, 1991-06-16; 33-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:06; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
    Merritt (B.C.); Ntlakyapamuk Indians--Food; Ntlakyapamuk Indians--Social life and customs; Ntlakyapamuk language
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-18; 33-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:06; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-06-18; 33-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:51; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-06-17; 34-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:19; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-06-17; 34-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:44; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
    Low sound levels from 2:01 to 3:45.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-07-24; 35-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:15; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-07-24; 35-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:45; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-07-25; 36-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:09; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-07-25; 36-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:42; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-07-26; 37-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:20; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Narrative about berry picking, 1991-07-26; 37-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:42; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
    Berries--Harvesting; Lower Nicola (B.C.); Ntlakyapamuk language
  - Narrative about digging for roots and basket making, 1991-07-26; 37-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:32; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
    Basket making; Lower Nicola (B.C.); Ntlakyapamuk Indians--Food; Ntlakyapamuk language
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-07-26; 37-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:13; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-07-28; 38-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:17; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1991-07-28; 38-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:12; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Narrative about wood gathering, 1991-07-28; 38-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:20; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
    Narrative given in Ntlakyapamuk only.
    Fuelwood gatherers; Merritt (B.C.); Ntlakyapamuk Indians--Economic conditions
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-07-29; 39-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1991-07-29; 39-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:52; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1992-03-17; 40-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:09; Contlee, Mary; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1992-03-17; 40-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:10; Contlee, Mary; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
    Sound quality slightly deteriorates from 5:36 through the end of the recording.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1992-03-18; 41-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:17; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1992-03-18; 41-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:17; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1992-03-19; 42-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:16; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1992-03-19; 42-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:49; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1992-03-20; 43-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:23; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1992-03-20; 43-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:52; Joe, Mabel; Kroeber, Paul D.
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1992-03-20; 44-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:26; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1992-03-20; 44-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:26; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical elicitation, 1992-03-20; 45-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:26; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) grammatical and lexical elicitation, 1992-03-20; 45-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:04; Kroeber, Paul D.; York, Kathy